PERFECT DAYS
Hello.
Sorry, there was a lot of traffic.
I hate the morning shift.
There is always vomit everywhere.
Like the other day
at Nanago Dori Park...
...in Hatagaya.
It was a real nightmare.
Some guy took
forever to get out.
8 out of 10 on the horror scale!
Are you even listening to me?
Take it easy, Mr. Hiyarama.
It'll just get dirty again anyway.
Mama!
What's wrong?
Are you here with your mom?
Everything will be fine.
Yosuke?
Mom was looking for you!
Where have you been?
Mom was looking for you everywhere!
Didn't I say
not to go too far?
I searched the whole park!
I'm sorry, honey.
Now he's crying too.
I'm sorry.
It's alright now
How the hell does this work?
Thank you very much.
Hello, welcome.
Welcome back!
For all your hard work!
Yes! He hit the ball!
He's in, right?
He's in! See?
Hey! What are you doing?
Playing bets?
Where's the fun?
Kat-chan! Back off!
Always respect other people's
sports teams or religions. High five!
Now go away. Alright!
They play dirty.
They steal great players
from other teams.
Oh my god!
Aya! You made it!
What a surprise! 10 out of 10!
Just a second!
This is the last place.
I'm almost done!
So you can work fast when you want to.
There's a girl waiting for me.
I'm done for today.
Come on!
Mr. Hiyarama,
may I borrow your car?
I can't miss this chance tonight.
Mr. Hiyarama, please!
I'm begging you!
Come on, please.
This is Mr. Hiyarama,
my supervisor at work.
Hard worker, but very quiet.
I don't even know what his voice sounds like.
Mr. Hiyarama, this is Aya.
Definitely a 10 out of 10!
Stop saying that.
Is it alright if I play this?
Mr. Hiyarama...
I like her voice.
Yeah?
Smith?
Very common name.
Mr. Hiyarama...
...do you really like this job?
You have your own equipment and tools.
How can you work so
hard at a job like this?
You don't have to answer.
I'm just curious.
This guy is weird.
9 out of 10 on the weirdness scale.
I like the sound of cassettes.
Yes! The cassette sounds great!
It's my first time listening to one.
The first time is always good!
Drop me off there.
Aren't we on a date?
I have an extra shift at the bar.
If you come,
I'll be with you all evening.
I'm still waiting for my paycheck.
Mr. Hiyarama, this is very important to me.
People can't fall in love
without money.
What happened to this world?
Is this the modern era?
How much is this worth?
Don't you want to know?
I'm just curious!
Analog is back in style.
These could be worth a lot.
I'm really just curious!
I know a good place in Shimokiti.
That's too far away.
It'll take less than 30 minutes.
It should be here...
Here it is! That's the sign.
Excuse me.
Welcome.
Excuse me, how much are these worth?
This one is rare, it's Lou Reed.
For this, 12 thousand yen.
Seriously?
For this 8000.
~ Really?
Where did you get these tapes?
They belong to my boss.
This one is 4000 yen.
Seriously?
This one can be sold for 6000.
You can make a lot of money from these.
Here is my estimate.
My goodness!
Amazing! Mr. Hiyarama,
let's sell them!
We'll take them all.
Cassettes are trending.
Especially cassettes
from the 70s and 80s.
We have to sell it,
your entire collection.
Twelve thousand
just for this tape!
Now is the perfect time!
OK, just one.
We'll just sell one.
Then I can go to the bar and see Aya.
This is a very important night for me.
This is a very important night for me!
If I miss this chance...
No love life if we're broke?
Isn't that true?
Really?
Thank you so much!
You saved me! I'm going!
You're the best, Mr. Hiyarama!
Thanks for coming.
Have a good night.
Thank you!
Mr. Hiyarama...
I don't think I have a chance with Aya.
Odds are 2 out of 10.
But that doesn't mean I give up.
Mr. Hiyarama...
You're not married, are you?
Alone at your age...
Don't you ever feel lonely?
Takashi!
Oh, hey!
We haven't seen each other for a long time.
~ Takashi!
What's up?
I was looking for you.
Were you?
~ Yes.
Mr. Hiyarama, this is Dera-chan,
a friend of mine.
As you can see, he likes my ears.
Every time he finds me, he grabs them.
He always finds me. 10 out of 10.
Dera-chan is friends with my ears,...
...and I'm just the accessory, right?
Yes.
~ Or not?
You are!
Excuse me!
I wanted to give this back to you.
Here.
Can I listen to it
one more time?
Thank you.
Did Takashi say anything?
Welcome back.
For all your hard work!
Hello.
Thanks.
BOOKS FOR 100 YEN
"Trees"
Aya Koda
Aya Koda should be more famous.
He uses the same words we do,
but does something special with them.
Good evening, Mr. Hiyarama.
The usual?
What are you reading now?
Aya Koda "Trees"
The essays?
Have you read it?
You're quite the intellectual.
No, I don't think so.
Here's your potato salad...
...and here's to a long day.
Mama, I didn't get that appetizer.
I'm sure I gave you one.
We had some but
we never got that much.
That is not true.
We're all equal here, right?
I'm gonna have to look up
"equality" in the dictionary.
Ah, women don't like petty men.
Have you always had a wrinkle here?
No no, on the other side. Here.
Mama, do you have fried tofu?
No, we ran out.
I'll make it if you go buy some.
His wife left him, you know.
How can he be so cheerful?
Are you talking about me?
No, it's nothing.
How can you be so cheerful
when your wife left you?
It's easy. Finally I'm
carefree and single again.
It makes all men happy.
What a relief to be rid
of fussy women.
You're just pretending to be strong.
Soon you'll be crying to Mama here
about how lonely you are.
It's always the same story...
One more drink?
Here.
Why can't things
just stay the same?
Mama.
Sing us that song.
Our favorite.
Oh, yes!
But Mr. Hiyarama has just arrived.
Don't let us down.
~ Please!
Here it is, that's it.
Come on.
Since you've already got the guitar out... Let's go.
It's a beautiful song.
I got to the place
in New Orleans
to a place they called a brothel
"The House of the Rising Sun"
The man I loved
he didn't come back.
That's when I left
your homeland.
I got on the train,
and in a moment...
And two hard lemonades!
Ah, you made it, just a moment!
For all your hard work!
Uncle.
Where were you?
I've been waiting for a long time.
Which door is your house?
Upstairs or downstairs?
Niko?
You've grown so much!
Uncle...
...you're going to work?
can I go with you?
You'd better take me with you.
if you leave me alone
I don't know what I'll do.
Get in from the other side.
Would you like a coffee?
Sure.
The same as mine?
Yeah.
Thank you.
You want to put it in?
~ Yes.
No, no.
This side.
Like this?
~ Yes.
The tape is on this side.
Is that the Sky Tree?
Yes, it is.
So, this is a cassette?
Like from ancient times?
From ancient times.
Can I play this
on my iPhone?
What does it say?
Van Morrison.
Is this on Spotify?
I don't know.
Where is that?
What?
That shop.
It's not a shop.
Ah, that thing!
You mean this?
My camera is quite old.
Look!
How?
You don't remember?
You gave it to me, Uncle.
Oh yes.
~ Liar.
You don't remember, do you?
Is the tree your friend?
Friend?
Is it?
I guess it is.
This is my friend the tree.
Uncle?
Is it alright if I borrow this book?
Which one?
"Eleven Short Stories"
Of course.
This boy, Victor,
from the tale "The Turtle"...
He's like me.
I understand what he's going through.
Is it alright if I help?
Really?
Thanks.
Uncle, why don't you and
my mom get along?
Is that what she told you?
Every time I talk about you...
...she changes the subject.
Is that so.
Did you have a fight with your mom?
Something like that.
Do you always run away from home?
This is my first time.
It was always my plan to
come live with you, Uncle.
What does that mean?
Hello.
Here you go.
Thank you. I go over there?
See you in 10 minutes.
That's too short.
20 minutes then.
Yes. I understand.
Yes, okay.
Are you hungry?
Then we'll have lunch.
~ Yay!
Put the towel here.
~ Thank you.
You and my mom
are nothing alike.
What do you mean?
She said you live in a
different world than we do.
That's probably true.
Is it?
This world is made
of many different worlds.
Some are related and some are not.
My world...
...and your mother's world
are very different.
What about mine?
What world am I in?
This river goes to the ocean?
Yes, to the ocean.
Can we go there?
Next time.
When will that be?
Next time is next time.
And when is that exactly?
Now is now.
Next time is next time.
Brother.
It's been a long time.
So you live here?
I'm not trying to be rude.
Niko, get your things.
I don't want to!
~ That's not an option.
Uncle!
Hurry up.
Come visit whenever you want.
I haven't even finished
reading your book.
You can take it with you.
I'll be like Victor.
No, you won't.
Don't say that.
~ Niko!
For your trouble.
Your favorite chocolate.
She's a good kid.
I'm not so sure about that.
Our father...
...he doesn't remember anything anymore.
Are you going to visit him
at the nursing home?
He won't behave like last time.
Is it true that you work cleaning toilets?
Uncle.
Thank you.
It's Takashi.
It's Takashi, hello?
I hear you.
Mr. Hiyarama, you have been
kind to me. I really appreciate it.
9 out of 10!
That's why it's hard for
me to say this, but I quit.
What?
I'll pay you back soon.
Wait a minute,
what about your shift?
Yes.
We can't find a replacement
on such short notice.
No replacement?
What should I do?
You'll have to cover the shift today.
What?
Can I? Sorry, I'll be quick.
Sorry.
Excuse me!
Are you new?
~ I'm almost done.
What is it?
Where's Takashi?
I've called three times.
Why isn't anyone picking up?
Listen, I'm only doing this for today.
Find someone, okay?
I'm Sato. I was told
to come here right away...
...and take over the shift
from the previous employee.
Should I start there?
Ah... Yes.
Hello.
~ Hello.
Do you remember what
used to be here?
That means we're getting old.
Patricia Highsmith knows
everything about anxiety.
She showed me that fear
and anxiety are different things.
What are you doing here?
You know...
Can i come in?
Come in.
A pack of cigarettes and a bag.
Can I have one?
I haven't smoked for a long time.
You saw us at the bar earlier?
It seems like you're always there.
Yes.
Since it opened, five
or six years ago.
Is that so.
It's a nice place.
I'm her ex-husband.
Ah, I see.
It's been about seven
years since we divorced.
I've gotten remarried.
It's been seven years
since I last saw her.
I have cancer.
And it has spread.
My body is swollen from the chemotherapy.
Then I...
...suddenly felt that
I owed her an apology.
Nothing bad happened.
Maybe it wasn't an apology.
I wanted to thank her.
No, that's not it either.
I just wanted to
see her, that's all.
Do you want a drink?
No thanks.
~ I still have one more.
In that case...
...I'll take one.
Please take care of her.
No, we don't have that kind of relationship.
~ I'm counting on you.
It's not like that.
Shadows...
Do they get darker
when they overlap?
I don't know.
There are still so many things I don't understand.
That's how life goes.
I guess that's how it is.
Let's go find out right now.
What?
Stand there.
What do you see?
Looks the same to me.
Isn't it darker?
I doubt it.
That looks darker to me.
I don't see the difference.
Here, look!
They must get darker!
It's only logical.
You're so persistent.
Still no changes?
Just forget it.
I agree.
Want to play shadow tag?
I'm the one chasing.
Ready?
I start.
Run!
Are you okay?
~ This is hard.
Now I'm the one chasing.
Are you sure? ~ Ready?
~ I start.
Got you!
Very hard.
This is tiring. Got you!
That was close. I stepped on you.
~ Did you?
I did.